SPEAKER 1: In this lab, your task is going to be to write a program to simulate population growth.
Let's imagine that we have a population of animals, a population of llamas, for example.
Every year, we lose some animals from that population as older llamas die.
But we also gain some animals to that population as new llamas are born.
We can model this kind of population growth using a mathematical formula.
Let's assume, for example, that every year, if we have a population of n llamas, we gain n divided by 3 llamas and we lose n divided by 4 llamas.
So in a population of 12 llamas, for example, in the next year, we would gain 12 divided by 3, or four new llamas.
And we would lose at 12 divided by 4, or losing three llamas, in that case.
Given this setup, we could ask ourselves a question.
For example, we could ask, how many years would it take to go from 20 llamas in a population to 30 llamas in a population?
Right now for example, we have 20 llamas in this population.
But after one year we would gain 20 divided by 3 llamas.
Now notice here that 20 doesn't divide evenly into three.
And as a result, we need to just truncate whatever would come after the decimal.
The actual answer is going to be six point something.
But because we can't have a fraction of an animal, we're just going to truncate whatever is after the decimal and say that we're gaining six llamas.
And we're going to lose 20 divided by 4, which nicely equals five llamas.
So after one year, we will now have 21 llamas.
We can then repeat the process and consider what might happen in the next year.
In the next year, we would gain 21 divided by 3, or seven llamas.
And we would lose 21 divided by 4, truncating whatever is after the decimal, losing five llamas.
Meaning we have a net change of two llamas.
Which means that after two years, we now have 23 llamas.
After the next year, we would gain seven llamas, lose five, for a new total of 25 llamas after three years.
In the next year, we would gain eight llamas and lose six, for a new total of 27 llamas after four years.
And then in the fifth year, we would gain at nine llamas and lose six for a total now of 30 llamas after five years.
So the answer to the question, how many years would it take to go from a population of 20 llamas to a population of 30 llamas is five years.
Now we did all of that math manually.
But your task now is going to be to write a program in C that can do that calculation for us.
The program will work like this.
At the command line, you'll run a program, ./population.
And at that point, your program should prompt the user for a starting population size.
You might type of starting population size of 100, for example.
Then your program should prompt the user for an ending population size.
And the user will type in another population size, say 200, for example.
Then your program should figure out how many years it would take to bring the population of llamas from the starting size to the ending size, and then print out that number of years.
So in this case, our program would print years colon 9 because it would take nine years to bring the population from 100 to 200.
So in summary, here's what you have to do.
First, start by prompting the user for the starting population size of your population of llamas.
And you should check to make sure that the user's input is at least nine.
The population size needs to be at least nine so that we can actually start to grow this population of llamas.
So if the user types in a number that's less than nine, you should keep re-prompting the user to type in a number again until they give you a number that's at least nine.
Next, you should prompt the user for the ending population size, here making sure that the user's input is at least as large as the starting size.
It wouldn't make sense, for example, to imagine the population going from a population of 100 to a population of 50 because the population is always going to be growing.
So you'll want to make sure that the end population size is greater than or equal to the starting population size.
If the user tries to type in an end population size that is less than the starting population size, then your program should continually re-prompt the user to type in another ending population size
until they provide you one that is at least the starting population size.
After that, your program should calculate how many years would be required to bring the population from the starting size to the ending size,
recalling that every year we are going to add n divided by 3 llamas, if there are n llamas to begin with.
And we're going to lose n divided by 4 llamas.
And as with before, because we can't have fractions of a llama, if either of those computations ends up with something after the decimal,
you're going to truncate or ignore what comes after that decimal when doing your math.
Finally, after you've made that calculation, you'll print the number of years required.
Printing years colon and then the number of years that would be required to bring the population up to that ending population size.
As you start working on this problem, there are a few strategies that might prove helpful.
One is a do while loop, a type of loop that lets you prompt the user one or more times for something, in this case.
So in the loop you're seeing here, we start by declaring a variable called n.
And then inside of a loop, we prompt the user for a positive integer, storing that integer inside of n.
But we're going to keep repeating that loop as long as n is less than 1.
Meaning if the user doesn't type in a positive integer, then we're going to prompt the user again.
You won't use this exact code inside of your lab but you might use something similar, both when you're prompting for the starting population size
to make sure that the starting population size is at least nine, and also when prompting for the end population size to make sure that the end population size is at least as
large as the starting population size.
You might also find it helpful to update a variable as you go about working on this lab.
You might want to repeatedly update your population size variable, for example, in order to add new llamas and get rid of older llamas.
You might do that using a formula like this.
If you have a variable called n inside of which is your current population, you can update the value of n for the next year using a line that says n equals n plus n over 3, the number of llamas
we're adding, minus n over 4, the number of llamas that we're losing in that particular year.
And finally, once you've completed the calculation, you can print out a variable using the print f function, saying, printf years colon, and then %i, we're %i is going to stand in for an integer.
Which Integer Well, that you specify after a comma.
And here we're saying, print out the value of n as the integer to print to the user.
Let's now take a look at the distribution code that we give you as a starting point for this problem.
Here in population.c, we've already included cs50.h and stdio.h for you.
And then giving you a main function with a few to dos to get started.
You're going to first prompt for the start size, then prompt for the n size.
Then calculate how many years it's going to take in order to reach that threshold value from the start size to the n size.
And then finally, once you've done that computation, printing out the number of years that would be required to take you from the start to the end.
Once you've written all of those pieces, you should then be able to compile your program and then run it, giving your program a starting population size and an ending population size.
And then your program should be able to tell you how long it will take to get from point A to point B. My name is Brian.
And this was population growth.
发言人 1：在这个实验室里，你们的任务是编写一个模拟人口增长的程序。
假设我们有一群动物，比如一群骆驼。
每年，随着老骆驼的死亡，我们都会失去一些骆驼。
但随着新骆驼的出生，我们也会增加一些骆驼数量。
我们可以用数学公式来模拟这种人口增长。
举例来说，假设我们每年有 n 只骆驼，那么我们会得到 n 除以 3 的骆驼数量，同时也会失去 n 除以 4 的骆驼数量。
因此，以 12 只美洲驼为例，明年我们将获得 12 除以 3，即 4 只新美洲驼。
如果是这样的话，我们就会以 12 除以 4 的方式输掉比赛，或者说输掉三只骆驼。
在这种情况下，我们可以问自己一个问题。
例如，我们可以问，从 20 只骆驼到 30 只骆驼需要多少年？
比如现在，我们有 20 只美洲驼。
但一年后，我们将获得 20 只骆驼除以 3 只。
现在请注意，20 并没有平均分成 3 份。
因此，我们需要截断小数点后的内容。
实际答案是六点几。
但因为我们不能用动物的分数来表示，所以我们只能截去小数点后面的部分，然后说我们获得了 6 只羊驼。
我们将失去 20 除以 4，正好等于五只骆驼。
因此，一年之后，我们将拥有 21 只骆驼。
然后，我们可以重复这一过程，并考虑下一年可能发生的情况。
下一年，我们将获得 21 除以 3，即 7 只骆驼。
我们会失去 21 除以 4，截去小数点后的数字，失去五只骆驼。
也就是说，我们净变了两只骆驼。
也就是说，两年后，我们现在有 23 只骆驼了。
第二年后，我们将增加 7 只骆驼，减少 5 只，三年后骆驼总数将达到 25 只。
第二年，我们将增加 8 只骆驼，减少 6 只，四年后骆驼总数将达到 27 只。
到了第五年，我们将增加 9 只骆驼，减少 6 只，五年后骆驼总数将达到 30 只。
因此，从 20 只骆驼到 30 只骆驼需要多少年，这个问题的答案是五年。
现在我们都是手动计算的。
但你现在的任务是用 C 语言编写一个程序，帮我们完成计算。
程序将这样运行
在命令行中，你将运行一个程序 ./population。
此时，程序应提示用户起始种群数量。
例如，您可以输入 100 人的起始人口数。
然后，您的程序应提示用户最终的种群数量。
用户将输入另一个人口数量，例如 200。
然后，您的程序应该计算出骆驼的数量从起始数量增加到终止数量需要多少年，然后打印出这个年数。
因此，在这种情况下，我们的程序将打印年份冒号 9，因为需要 9 年时间才能将人口从 100 增至 200。
因此，总而言之，你必须这样做。
首先，提示用户骆驼的起始种群数量。
您还应该检查用户的输入是否至少为 9。
骆驼的数量至少要达到九只，这样我们才能真正开始增加骆驼的数量。
因此，如果用户键入的数字小于 9，你就应该不断再次提示用户键入数字，直到他们给出一个至少是 9 的数字。
接下来，你应该提示用户输入结束的种群数量，这里要确保用户输入的数量至少与起始数量一样大。
例如，想象人口从 100 人变为 50 人是没有意义的，因为人口总是在增长。
因此，您需要确保最终种群数量大于或等于起始种群数量。
如果用户尝试键入的结束种群数量小于起始种群数量，那么程序应不断重新提示用户键入另一个结束种群数量。
直到他们提供一个至少是起始种群数量的种群。
然后，您的程序应该计算出需要多少年才能使人口从起始规模达到终止规模、
回顾一下，如果一开始就有 n 只骆驼，那么每年我们都要加上 n 除以 3 的骆驼。
我们将失去 n 除以 4 的骆驼。
和以前一样，因为我们不能有骆驼的分数，如果其中任何一个计算结果在小数点后有东西的话、
在计算时，你要截断或忽略小数点后面的内容。
最后，在计算之后，您将打印出所需的年数。
然后是使人口数量达到最终人口数量所需的年数。
当你开始解决这个问题时，有一些策略可能会对你有所帮助。
一种是 do while 循环，这种循环可以让你提示用户一次或多次，在本例中就是这样。
因此，在你看到的循环中，我们首先声明一个名为 n 的变量。
然后在一个循环中，我们会提示用户输入一个正整数，并将该整数存储在 n 中。
但只要 n 小于 1，我们就会一直重复这个循环。
也就是说，如果用户没有输入正整数，我们就会再次提示用户。
您不会在实验室中使用完全相同的代码，但您可能会在提示起始种群数量时使用类似的代码
确保起始种群数量至少为 9，在提示最终种群数量时，也要确保最终种群数量至少为
与起始种群规模一样大。
在实验过程中，您可能会发现更新变量也很有帮助。
例如，您可能需要反复更新种群数量变量，以便添加新的骆驼和淘汰旧的骆驼。
您可以使用这样的公式来计算。
如果您有一个名为 n 的变量，其中包含当前的人口数量，您就可以更新下一年的 n 值，只需在一行中写明 n 等于 n 加上 n 超过 3，即骆驼的数量。
我们再加上 n，减去 4，就是当年损失的骆驼数量。
最后，完成计算后，您可以使用 print f 函数打印出一个变量，例如，printf 年冒号，然后是 %i，我们的 %i 将代表一个整数。
您在逗号后指定的整数。
在这里，我们是说，将 n 的值作为整数打印出来，打印给用户。
现在让我们来看看我们为您提供的分发代码，作为解决这个问题的起点。
在 population.c 中，我们已经为您加入了 cs50.h 和 stdio.h。
然后为您提供一个主要功能，其中包括一些入门必做事项。
首先提示起始尺寸，然后提示 n 尺寸。
然后计算从起始规模到 n 规模需要多少年才能达到临界值。
最后，计算完毕后，打印出从起点到终点所需的年数。
写完所有这些部分后，您就可以编译程序并运行它，从而得出起始种群数量和终止种群数量。
然后你的程序就能告诉你从 A 点到 B 点需要多长时间。
这就是人口增长。